<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">"Handsfree"</string>
    <string name="reconnect">"Reconnect"</string>
    <string name="open_contacts">"Select contacts"</string>
    <string name="open_connectiq_store">"Open watch app in Connect IQ"</string>
    <string name="open_hints_for_background">"Run it in the background"</string>
    <string name="permissions_explanation_markdown">"## Introduction

Handsfree lets you keep your phone in your pocket while you make calls, allowing you to use Garmin watch for initiating and/or controlling the calls.

To have the best experience for making the calls from the watch, while leaving your phone in the pocket, it needs a few permissions from you: some of them are quite crucial, some not, please find the explanation for each of those below and grant them as necessary (please note that you can always adjust them at any point in time later via the app settings).

## Permissions

### Make and manage calls

To be able to initiate, observe and hangup calls from your watch, Handsfree needs permission from you to make and manage calls.

If you don't give this permission. Handsfree will have very little use, because it won't be able to do much with the calls on the phone for you.

### Access your call logs

To be able to identify the number of a call in progress, Handsfree needs access to your call logs.

If you give this permission, you will be able to see the number (and probably the contact name), on the watch.

If you don't give this permission, you'll see \"Unreadable\" instead of the number or the contact name for calls in progress.

### Access your contacts

To let you see the predefined list of the contacts that you can use for outgoing calls on your watch, as well as to display a matching contact name during a call in progress, on your watch, Handsfree needs permission to access your contacts.

If you don't give this permission, you won't be able to dial the contacts from the watch.

### Display over other apps

To be able to make calls via the standard phone app while running in the background, Handsfree needs the permission to display over other apps.

If you don't give this permission, Handsfree will not be able to make calls when it is not the frontmost application or when the phone is locked. This permission is not necessary for observing or hanging up calls in progress though.

### Always run in background

To be able to serve your requests while it's not the frontmost application, Handsfree needs the permission to always run in background.

If you don't give this permission, you'll still be able to use it in foreground, but it will be stopped by the system soon after you switch to other apps.

### Send you notifications

To be able to serve your request while working in background, Handsfree needs the permission to show you a notification. This is a measure for you to be sure that it's running in the background/awaiting for your requests from the watch. It also shows you a bit of current status of the connection to your watch.

If you don't give this permission, you'll still be able to use it in foreground, but it will be eventually stopped by the system after the app is put into the background, as it's required for these kinds of apps running in the background to always show the notification.

"</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_proceed_title">"Handsfree permissions"</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_proceed_btn">"Grant permissions"</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_app_settings_btn">"App settings"</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_do_not_proceed_btn">"Cancel"</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_all_granted_title">"Handsfree permissions"</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_all_granted_ok_btn">"OK"</string>
    <string name="app_logo_description">"App logo"</string>
    <string name="onboarding_essentials">"# Control calls from the watch

As a bare minimum, Handsfree lets you observe and hangup calls in progress, without sharing any personal information with the watch. The only information that is shared is the fact that there's an unidentified call in progress.

To provide this minimum functionality, Handsfree needs a few essential permissions from you.

### [Make and manage calls](permissions://?manifest=android.permission.CALL_PHONE,android.permission.ANSWER_PHONE_CALLS,android.permission.READ_PHONE_STATE)

To be able to observe and hangup calls from your watch, Handsfree needs the permission from you to make and manage calls.

Without the permission, Handsfree won't be able to perform much of its job, as it won't be able to see a call in progress to show you the call status on the watch, neither it would be able to hangup a call on your request from the watch.

### [Always run in background](permissions://?battery_optimization)

To be able to serve your requests while it's not the frontmost application, Handsfree needs the permission to always run in background.

Without the permission, you'll still be able to use it while it's in the foreground, but it will be stopped by the system soon after you switch to other apps or e.g. lock your phone.

### [Send you notifications](permissions://?manifest=android.permission.POST_NOTIFICATIONS)

To be able to serve your request while working in background, Handsfree needs the permission to show you a notification. This is a measure for you to be sure that it's running in the background/awaiting for your requests from the watch. It also shows you a bit of current status of the connection to your watch.

Without the permission, the system will stop Handsfree soon after it switches to the background.

## Running it in the background

Besides the above permissions, to let Handsfree run without interruptions, check **[the known hints for running Android apps in background, on your particular phone model](do://doki).**

"</string>
    <string name="onboarding_outgoing_calls">"# Allow outgoing calls

Handsfree lets you make outgoing calls from the watch for your [starred contacts](contacts://starred) or for your recent calls, by redirecting your requests from the watch to the default phone application.

Beware that even though you can open starred contacts from Handsfree, it has no access to the list until you give it the permission to access the list.

If you want to use outgoing calls on your watch, you need to give Handsfree a few permissions, **in addition** to the [essential ones](link://onboarding_essentials).

### [Display over other apps](permissions://?draw_overlays)

To be able to make calls via the default phone app while running in the background, Handsfree needs the permission to display over other apps.

Without the permission, Handsfree won't be able to make calls for you, when it is not the frontmost application or when the phone is locked. This permission is not necessary for observing or hanging up calls in progress though.



"</string>
    <string name="navigation_onboarding">"Configuration"</string>
    <string name="onboarding_intro">"Version {{version_info}}

### [Troubleshooting](link://onboarding_troubleshooting)

### [Project home](https://github.com/grigorye/Handsfree)

### Getting Handsfree on a Garmin device

A. [Handsfree app](https://apps.garmin.com/en-US/apps/73107243-f322-4cf2-bb3d-78f2a4ee8920) for recent devices (not older than 2022), that have support for glances in apps:

[&lt;img src=\"./badges/Connect-IQ/Connect-IQ-Badge_White.svg\" max-height=\"160\" alt=\"Open Connect IQ\"/&gt;](https://apps.garmin.com/en-US/apps/73107243-f322-4cf2-bb3d-78f2a4ee8920)

B. [Handsfree widget](https://apps.garmin.com/apps/629f3ba5-66bc-4b44-a078-3365a85212f8) for *older generations* of Garmin devices:

[&lt;img src=\"./badges/Connect-IQ/Connect-IQ-Badge_White.svg\" max-height=\"160\" alt=\"Open Connect IQ\"/&gt;](https://apps.garmin.com/apps/629f3ba5-66bc-4b44-a078-3365a85212f8)

### Keeping Handsfree companion up to date

A. With Google Play:

[&lt;img src=\"./badges/Google-Play/Get-It-On-Google-Play-Badge_en.svg\" max-height=\"160\" alt=\"Get it on Google Play\"/&gt;](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.gentin.connectiq.handsfree) 

B. If you prefer to not depend on Google Play, you can install the latest version of the app using the link below:

#### [Install the latest version without Google Play](https://grigorye.github.io/handsfree/Installation)

### Beta testing

If you're interested in beta testing, please send a request to join the [dedicated Google group](https://groups.google.com/g/handsfree-beta).

### Feedback

Reach to &lt;garmin9E96E@icloud.com&gt; or the [beta testing group](https://groups.google.com/g/handsfree-beta). All the feedback is highly appreciated.

"</string>
    <string name="navigation_overview">"About"</string>
    <string name="permissions_snackbar_app_settings_btn">"App Settings"</string>
    <string name="overview_snackbar_reconnecting_connectiq">"Reconnecting…"</string>
    <string name="permissions_snackbar_permission_is_already_granted">"The permission is already there."</string>
    <string name="permissions_snackbar_permission_is_denied">"The permission is available in App Settings."</string>
    <string name="settings_essentials">"Call control"</string>
    <string name="settings_essentials_on">"Calls can be observed and hang up on the watch."</string>
    <string name="settings_essentials_off">"No calls are enabled on the watch."</string>
    <string name="settings_contacts">"🟢 Phonebook"</string>
    <string name="settings_contacts_on">"Some contacts are starred and should be available on the watch."</string>
    <string name="settings_contacts_off">"**Starred** contacts make the list for dialing from the watch."</string>
    <string name="settings_outgoing_calls">"Outgoing calls"</string>
    <string name="settings_outgoing_calls_off">"Making calls is not possible on the watch."</string>
    <string name="settings_outgoing_calls_on">"Making calls is possible on the watch."</string>
    <string name="settings_disabled_due_to_essentials_are_off">"Disabled due to basic call control is off."</string>
    <string name="onboarding_troubleshooting">"# Troubleshooting

There are several components that should work together for normal operation of Handsfree. If it does not work as expected, especially when your setup changes (e.g. you added or removed Garmin device, got new phone or OS update), try the hints below. They cover all the known problems so far.

### In general/beforehand

**Make sure that the watch app is _not_ installed and running on multiple Garmin devices, simultaneously**: that's known to cause all kinds of troubles. Either install it on a single Garmin device or try to keep only one device running Handsfree, connected to your phone.

**[Follow hints for running apps in background on your phone](do://doki)** - this is crucial to do after you first install the app.

**[Check Handsfree app settings](do://settings)** to make sure the necessary permissions are given, it's not blocked from running in the background by something extra and etc.

### If things go wrong out of sudden

**[Force stop Garmin Connect](do://garmin-connect-settings)** - this may be the dealbreaker when Handsfree does not respond to watch app (things happen) - just tap \"Force stop\" to kill the app (there's no need to restart it - that will be done automatically). Sometimes it needs to be followed by resetting the connection to the phone, see below.

**Toggle the connection to your phone off and then back on from the settings on your Garmin device** - this is known to help when the phone does not respond to your commands from the watch app.

**[Reconnect with the watch](do://reconnect-connectiq)** (you can tap the devices list on the Control screen to reconnect as well) - this may be worth trying, especially if you don't want to kill Garmin Connect (see above).

**Reboot your phone** - yes, that may mean a lot, but it's for sure probably the simplest thing to do once in a while.

### May be helpful in certain situations

**[Toggle debug mode](do://toggle-debug-mode)** - only if asked, or you want to see the internal stats instead of the usual notification content.

**[Save Log](do://share-log)** - only if asked, to debug the app.

**[Restart the service](do://restart-service)** - as an alternative to force stopping the app.

**[Open app on the watch](do://open-watch-app)** - just to check that it's there.

**[Open app in Connect IQ](do://open-app-in-store)** - e.g. to check the latest version (it does not work reliably, though).

**[Ping app on the watch](do://ping)** - to verify the connection.

**[Toggle watch simulator](do://toggle-emulator-mode)** - should be used for development only.
"</string>
    <string name="settings_essentials_group">"Essentials"</string>
    <string name="settings_extras_group">"Extras"</string>
    <string name="settings_screen">"Controls"</string>
    <string name="settings_preference_disabled_fmt">"❎ {{title}}"</string>
    <string name="settings_preference_enabled_fmt">"✅ {{title}}"</string>
    <string name="settings_devices_group">"Devices"</string>
    <string name="settings_preferences_subscreen">"Configuration"</string>
    <string name="device_label_connected">"Connected"</string>
    <string name="device_label_not_connected">"Not Connected"</string>
    <string name="onboarding_incoming_calls">"# Allow incoming calls

Handsfree lets you show and accept the incoming calls on the watch. To fully benefit from that, give the app a couple more permissions, in addition to the [essential ones](link://onboarding_essentials).

### [Access your phone call logs](permissions://?manifest=android.permission.READ_CALL_LOG)

To be able to identify the number for an incoming call, Handsfree needs access to your call logs.

Without the permission, for an incoming call, Handsfree will display a generic message like \"Call in Progress\" instead of the phone number or the contact name, on the watch.

With the permission, Handsfree will be able to show you the number (and probably the contact name) on the watch.

## On the watch

When enabled, Handsfree forwards your calls to the watch, so you can see an incoming call *when the watch app is active*.

To actually **get alerted** (or not) about an incoming call *when the watch app is not active*, toggle \"Incoming Calls\" in the app settings.

&lt;img src=\"./badges/Watch/Settings-Incoming-Calls.jpg\" alt=\"Settings-Incoming-Calls\" style=\"zoom:50%;\" /&gt;
"</string>
    <string name="settings_incoming_calls">"Incoming calls"</string>
    <string name="settings_incoming_calls_off">"Not receiving calls on the watch."</string>
    <string name="settings_incoming_calls_on">"Calls can be accepted on the watch."</string>
    <string name="settings_recents">"Recents"</string>
    <string name="settings_recents_off">"Call history is not shared with the watch."</string>
    <string name="settings_recents_on">"Recently called contacts are shared with the watch."</string>
    <string name="onboarding_recents">"# Recents

Handsfree lets you see and make calls to recently contacted parties, as well as track missed calls, on the watch. To allow that, give the app a couple more permissions, in addition to the [essential ones](link://onboarding_essentials).

### [Access your phone call logs](permissions://?manifest=android.permission.READ_CALL_LOG)

To let you see your recent calls on the watch, Handsfree needs access to your call logs.

Without the permission, recent calls cannot be shown on the watch.

With the permission, Handsfree will be able to show you the recent/missed calls, and let you call them back from the watch (if you enable outgoing calls).
"</string>
    <string name="onboarding_starred_contacts">"# Allow dialing of starred contacts

Handsfree lets you make outgoing calls to any of the starred contacts. To allow that, give the app the extra permission, in addition to the ones necessary for [outgoing calls](link://onboarding_outgoing_calls).

You can check your starred contacts [here](contacts://starred).

### [Access your contacts](permissions://?manifest=android.permission.READ_CONTACTS)

To let you dial a starred contact from your watch, Handsfree needs permission to access your contacts. Given the permission, Handsfree sends the contact names and phone numbers to the watch. Handsfree never reads nor sends any other contact information to anywhere.

Without the permission, the (starred) contacts won't be sent to the watch, and hence you won't be able to dial them from your watch.
"</string>
    <string name="settings_outgoing_calls_on_no_perm">"Making calls is not possible on the watch."</string>
    <string name="settings_preference_enabled_no_perm_fmt">"⚠️ {{title}}"</string>
    <string name="onboarding_call_info">"# Show caller info

Handsfree can let you see the phone number and contact name for a call, on the watch, like a normal phone. If you want to benefit from that for the calls that you did not initiate on the watch, give the app a couple more permissions, in addition to the [essential ones](link://onboarding_essentials).

### [Access your phone call logs](permissions://?manifest=android.permission.READ_CALL_LOG)

To be able to identify the phone number for a call, Handsfree needs access to your call logs.

With the permission, Handsfree will be able to show you the phone number (and probably the contact name, see below), on the watch.

Without the permission, Handsfree will display a generic message like \"Call in Progress\".

### [Access your contacts](permissions://?manifest_optional=android.permission.READ_CONTACTS)

To be able to match the phone number of a call with a contact name and show it on the watch, Handsfree needs access to your contacts, so that when it observes the call, it can send the matching contact name to show it to you on the watch.

Without the permission, no contact names for the calls will be visible.
"</string>
    <string name="settings_call_info">"Caller ID"</string>
    <string name="settings_call_info_off">"No phone numbers or names are shown on the watch."</string>
    <string name="settings_call_info_on">"Phone numbers or contact names are shown on the watch."</string>
    <string name="settings_starred_contacts">"Contacts"</string>
    <string name="settings_starred_contacts_off">"**Starred** contacts are not shared with the watch."</string>
    <string name="settings_starred_contacts_on">"**Starred** contacts are available for dialing on the watch."</string>
    <string name="settings_preference_not_available_fmt">"⛔️ {{title}}"</string>
    <string name="settings_call_info_unavailable">"Not available."</string>
    <string name="settings_recents_unavailable">"Not available."</string>
    <string name="settings_permission_not_available_rationale">"&gt; This permission is not currently available with this version of the app."</string>
    <string name="settings_device_with_symbol_fmt">"{{symbol}}\u00A0{{device_name}}"</string>
    <string name="settings_device_symbol_active">"⚡️"</string>
    <string name="settings_device_symbol_standby">"✅"</string>
    <string name="settings_device_symbol_missing_app">"⬇️️️"</string>
    <string name="settings_device_symbol_not_connected">"❌️"</string>
    <string name="settings_device_symbol_conflicting">"‼️"</string>
    <string name="settings_device_symbol_loading">"⏳"</string>
    <string name="settings_device_suffix_silent">"(ringing off)"</string>
    <string name="settings_permission_granted_fmt">"[✅ {{link_text}}]({{link_url}})"</string>
    <string name="settings_permission_not_granted_fmt">"[❎ {{link_text}}]({{link_url}})"</string>
    <string name="settings_permission_not_available_fmt">"[⛔️ {{link_text}}]({{link_url}})"</string>
    <string name="settings_no_devices_registered_message">"No devices are registered."</string>
    <string name="settings_no_devices_registered_suggestion">"Use Garmin Connect to register a device."</string>
</resources>