<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">"Handsfree"</string>
    <string name="reconnect">"Reconnect"</string>
    <string name="open_contacts">"Select contacts"</string>
    <string name="open_connectiq_store">"Open watch app in Connect IQ"</string>
    <string name="open_hints_for_background">"Run it in the background"</string>
    <string name="permissions_explanation_markdown">"## Introduction

Handsfree lets you keep your phone in your pocket while you make calls, allowing you to use Garmin watch for initiating and/or controlling the calls.

To have the best experience for making the calls from the watch, while leaving your phone in the pocket, it needs a few permissions from you: some of them are quite crucial, some not, please find the explanation for each of those below and grant them as necessary (please note that you can always adjust them at any point in time later via the app settings).

## Permissions

### Make and manage calls

To be able to initiate, observe and hangup calls from your watch, Handsfree needs permission from you to make and manage calls.

If you don't give this permission. Handsfree will have very little use, because it won't be able to do much with the calls on the phone for you.

### Access your call logs

To be able to identify the number of a call in progress, Handsfree needs access to your call logs.

If you give this permission, you will be able to see the number (and probably the contact name), on the watch.

If you don't give this permission, you'll see \"Unreadable\" instead of the number or the contact name for calls in progress.

### Access your contacts

To let you see the predefined list of the contacts that you can use for outgoing calls on your watch, as well as to display a matching contact name during a call in progress, on your watch, Handsfree needs permission to access your contacts.

If you don't give this permission, you won't be able to dial the contacts from the watch.

### Display over other apps

To be able to make calls via the standard phone app while running in the background, Handsfree needs the permission to display over other apps.

If you don't give this permission, Handsfree will not be able to make calls when it is not the frontmost application or when the phone is locked. This permission is not necessary for observing or hanging up calls in progress though.

### Always run in background

To be able to serve your requests while it's not the frontmost application, Handsfree needs the permission to always run in background.

If you don't give this permission, you'll still be able to use it in foreground, but it will be stopped by the system soon after you switch to other apps.

### Send you notifications

To be able to serve your request while working in background, Handsfree needs the permission to show you a notification. This is a measure for you to be sure that it's running in the background/awaiting for your requests from the watch. It also shows you a bit of current status of the connection to your watch.

If you don't give this permission, you'll still be able to use it in foreground, but it will be eventually stopped by the system after the app is put into the background, as it's required for these kinds of apps running in the background to always show the notification.

"</string>
    <string name="grant_permissions_btn">"Grant permissions"</string>
    <string name="show_permissions_btn">"Manage permissions"</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_proceed_title">"Handsfree permissions"</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_proceed_btn">"Grant permissions"</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_app_settings_btn">"App settings"</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_do_not_proceed_btn">"Cancel"</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_all_granted_title">"Handsfree permissions"</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_all_granted_ok_btn">"OK"</string>
    <string name="app_logo_description">"App logo"</string>
    <string name="intro_txt">"Handsfree runs in the background and serves your requests from the &lt;a href=\"https://apps.garmin.com/apps/a3d8da80-e013-41f9-aca4-f66bb38fad3f\"&gt;Garmin watch app&lt;/a&gt; (installed separately on the watch) to make calls on your phone.

Use the controls below to complete or adjust the setup."</string>
    <string name="select_contacts_hint">"Select the contacts to be shared with the watch app, to let you dial one of those later:"</string>
    <string name="give_permissions_hint">"Give the app permissions to manage calls, have access to the contacts, and run in the background in general:"</string>
    <string name="run_in_background_hint">"Let the app run in the background on your specific phone model:"</string>
    <string name="onboarding_welcome">"# Setting it up

Use the links below to help Handsfree do its job:

[**Run essentials**](permissions://?battery_optimization&amp;manifest=android.permission.CALL_PHONE,android.permission.ANSWER_PHONE_CALLS,android.permission.READ_PHONE_STATE,android.permission.POST_NOTIFICATIONS) [(guide)](link://onboarding_essentials)

[**Allow outgoing calls**](permissions://?draw_overlays&amp;manifest=android.permission.READ_CONTACTS) [(guide)](link://onboarding_outgoing_calls)

[**Allow control over other calls in progress**](permissions://?manifest=android.permission.READ_CALL_LOG&amp;android.permission.READ_CONTACTS) [(guide)️](link://onboarding_full_featured)

"</string>
    <string name="onboarding_essentials">"# Run essentials

As a bare minimum, Handsfree lets you observe and hangup calls in progress, without sharing any personal information with the watch. The only information that is shared is the fact that there's an unidentified call in progress.

If you want to benefit from the minimum functionality of Handsfree, you need to give it a few essential permissions:

### [Make and manage calls](permission://manifest?android.permission.CALL_PHONE&amp;android.permission.ANSWER_PHONE_CALLS&amp;android.permission.READ_PHONE_STATE)

To be able to observe and hangup calls from your watch, Handsfree needs permission from you to make and manage calls.

Without the permission, Handsfree will have very little use, because it won't be able to do much with the calls on the phone for you.

### [Always run in background](permission://battery_optimization)

To be able to serve your requests while it's not the frontmost application, Handsfree needs the permission to always run in background.

Without the permission, you'll still be able to use it in foreground, but it will be stopped by the system soon after you switch to other apps.

### [Send you notifications](permission://manifest?android.permission.POST_NOTIFICATIONS)

To be able to serve your request while working in background, Handsfree needs the permission to show you a notification. This is a measure for you to be sure that it's running in the background/awaiting for your requests from the watch. It also shows you a bit of current status of the connection to your watch.

Besides the above permissions, to let Handsfree run without interruptions, it's **strongly** recommended to take a look at **[known hints for running Android apps in background, on your particular phone model](do://doki).**

"</string>
    <string name="onboarding_outgoing_calls">"# Outgoing calls

Besides the essential functionality, Handsfree lets you make outgoing calls from the watch for your [starred contacts](contacts://starred), by redirecting your requests from the watch to the default phone application. 

Beware that even though you can open Contacts app/see the starred contacts with the above link, Handsfree itself has no access to the list until you give it permission for that.

If you want to use outgoing calls on your watch, you need to give Handsfree a few permissions, **in addition** to those required for the [bare minimum](link://onboarding_essentials) functionality:

### [Display over other apps](permission://draw_overlays)

To be able to make calls via the standard phone app while running in the background, Handsfree needs the permission to display over other apps.

Without the permission, Handsfree will not be able to make calls when it is not the frontmost application or when the phone is locked. This permission is not necessary for observing or hanging up calls in progress though.

### [Access your contacts](permission://manifest?android.permission.READ_CONTACTS)

To let you see the list of the starred contacts that you can use for outgoing calls on your watch on your watch, Handsfree needs permission to access your contacts. Given the permission, Handsfree sends the contact names and phone numbers to the watch. Handsfree never reads nor sends any other contact information to anywhere.

Without this permission, the (starred) contacts won't be available on the watch, and hence it will not be possible to dial the contacts from the watch.

"</string>
    <string name="onboarding_full_featured">"# Run most of the phone features on the watch

With Handsfree you can completely offload most of the phone call management to your watch: besides letting you make outgoing calls, Handsfree can show you the phone numbers and the names of the contacts for any calls in progress. If you want to benefit from that, you need to give Handsfree a couple more permissions, in addition to those required for [bare minimum outgoing calls](link://onboarding_outgoing_calls):

### [Access your phone call logs](permission://manifest?android.permission.READ_CALL_LOG)

To be able to identify the number of a call in progress, Handsfree needs access to your call logs. When it identifies a call in progress, Handsfree sends the phone number to the watch, so that it's displayed there.

Without this permission, you'll see \"Unreadable\" instead of the number or the contact name for calls in progress.

With this permission, Handsfree will be able to show you the number (and probably the contact name, see below), on the watch.

### [Access your contacts](permission://manifest?android.permission.READ_CONTACTS)

To be able to match the phone number of call in progress with a contact name and show it on the watch, Handsfree needs access to your contacts, so that when it identifies a call in progress, it can send the matching contact name to be displayed on the watch.

Without this permission, only the phone number will be visible on the watch (and that is only if you gave access to call logs to Handsfree).
"</string>
    <string name="navigation_onboarding">"Configuration"</string>
    <string name="onboarding_intro">"Handsfree lets you keep your phone in your pocket while you make calls, allowing you to use Garmin watch for initiating and/or controlling the calls. It's a companion application to the application that you can install on Garmin watch from [Connect IQ store](https://apps.garmin.com/apps/a3d8da80-e013-41f9-aca4-f66bb38fad3f).

### Troubleshooting

**[Reconnect to your watch](do://reconnect-connectiq)**

**[App settings](do://settings)**

**[Hints for running apps in background on your phone](do://doki)**
"</string>
    <string name="navigation_overview">"Overview"</string>
    <string name="permissions_snackbar_app_settings_btn">"App Settings"</string>
    <string name="overview_snackbar_reconnecting_connectiq">"Reconnecting…"</string>
    <string name="permissions_snackbar_permission_is_already_granted">"The permission is already there."</string>
    <string name="permissions_snackbar_permission_is_denied">"The permission is available in App Settings."</string>
    <string name="markdown_link_permission_granted_fmt">"[✅]({{link_url}})  [{{link_text}}]({{link_url}})"</string>
    <string name="markdown_link_permission_not_granted_fmt">"[❎]({{link_url}})  [{{link_text}}]({{link_url}})"</string>
</resources>