<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Handsfree</string>
    <string name="reconnect">Reconnect</string>
    <string name="open_contacts">Select contacts</string>
    <string name="open_connectiq_store">Open watch app in Connect IQ</string>
    <string name="open_hints_for_background">Run it in the background</string>
    <string name="permissions_explanation_markdown">## Introduction\n\nHandsfree lets you keep your phone in your pocket while you make calls, allowing you to use Garmin watch for initiating and/or controlling the calls.\n\nTo have the best experience for making the calls from the watch, while leaving your phone in the pocket, it needs a few permissions from you: some of them are quite crucial, some not, please find the explanation for each of those below and grant them as necessary (please note that you can always adjust them at any point in time later via the app settings).\n\n## Permissions\n\n### Access your call logs\n\nTo be able to identify the number of a call in progress, Handsfree needs access to your call logs.\n\nIf you give this permission, you will be able to see the number (and probably the contact name), on the watch.\n\nIf you don\'t give this permission, you\'ll see \"Unreadable\" instead of the number or the contact name for calls in progress.\n\n### Access your contacts\n\nTo let you see the predefined list of the contacts that you can use for outgoing calls on your watch, as well as to display a matching contact name during a call in progress, on your watch, Handsfree needs permission to access your contacts.\n\nIf you don\'t give this permission, you won\'t be able to dial the contacts from the watch.\n\n### Make and manage calls\n\nTo be able to initiate, observe and hangup calls from your watch, Handsfree needs permission from you to make and manage calls.\n\nIf you don\'t give this permission. Handsfree will have very little use, because it won\'t be able to do much with the calls on the phone for you.\n\n### Display over other apps\n\nTo be able to make calls via the standard phone app while running in the background, Handsfree needs the permission to display over other apps.\n\nIf you don\'t give this permission, Handsfree will not be able to make calls when it is not the frontmost application or when the phone is locked. This permission is not necessary for observing or hanging up calls in progress though.\n\n### Always run in background\n\nTo be able to serve your requests while it\'s not the frontmost application, Handsfree needs the permission to always run in background.\n\nIf you don\'t give this permission, you\'ll still be able to use it in foreground, but it will be stopped by the system soon after you switch to other apps.\n\n### Send you notifications\n\nTo be able to serve your request while working in background, Handsfree needs the permission to show you a notification. This is a measure for you to be sure that it\'s running in the background/awaiting for your requests from the watch. It also shows you a bit of current status of the connection to your watch.\n\nIf you don\'t give this permission, you\'ll still be able to use it in foreground, but it will be eventually stopped by the system after the app is put into the background, as it\'s required for these kinds of apps running in the background to always show the notification.\n\n</string>
    <string name="grant_permissions_btn">Grant permissions</string>
    <string name="show_permissions_btn">Manage permissions</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_proceed_title">Handsfree permissions</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_proceed_btn">Grant permissions</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_app_settings_btn">App settings</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_do_not_proceed_btn">Cancel</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_all_granted_title">Handsfree permissions</string>
    <string name="permissions_dialog_all_granted_ok_btn">OK</string>
    <string name="app_logo_description">App logo</string>
    <string name="intro_txt">Handsfree runs in the background and serves your requests from the <a href="https://apps.garmin.com/apps/a3d8da80-e013-41f9-aca4-f66bb38fad3f">Garmin watch app</a> (installed separately on the watch) to make calls on your phone.\n\nUse the controls below to complete or adjust the setup.</string>
    <string name="select_contacts_hint">Select the contacts to be shared with the watch app, to let you dial one of those later:</string>
    <string name="give_permissions_hint">Give the app permissions to manage calls, have access to the contacts, and run in the background in general:</string>
    <string name="run_in_background_hint">Let the app run in the background on your specific phone model:</string>

</resources>